# EMILY KRAUSE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

## CONTACT

217-721-5213

 $\vee$ 

elibertykrause@gmail.com



Chicago Area

#### EDUCATION

**BACHELOR OF ARTS** IN GRAPHIC DESIGN Carthage College

3.9 **GPA Ongoing** 

#### SECONDARY EDUCATION

Warren Township High School **High Honor Roll** 

2018 - 2022

## HARD SKILLS

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe After Effects

Adobe Premiere Pro

## SOFT SKILLS

Logo Creation

Motion Design

Social Media Marketing

Kinetic Typography

Creative Problem-Solving

Attention to Detail

Adaptability

Video Editing

Visual Communication

## SUMMARY

I am a graphic designer with seven years of experience in motion design and Adobe suite programs. Great attention to detail. Dedicated to clear and concise visual communication. Current student at Carthage College in pursuit of my Bachelor of Arts in Graphic Design.

## EXPERIENCE

#### VIDEO PRODUCTION INTERN

Carthage College - Marketing & Communications Office

## **2023 - Present**

- Producing B-Roll for college website
- Directing & editing marketing campaign footage
- Directing cast and crew
- Audio/Visual technician

## MOTION GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Interstellar Digital - Marketing Agency

# 2022

- Creating motion design video aimed at clientele
- Graphic design consultant

## TYPOGRAPHER / MOTION DESIGNER

Arcanus 55 / Web Tool Toys

## 2020 - 2023

- Creating website logo and components
- Kinetic typography and vector content
- Promotional website videos

# PORTFOLIO LINK







# EXTRACURRICULARS

## **DIRECTOR OF PROMOTIONS**

Carthage Film Association

## 2022 - Present

- Managing social media accounts
- Editing trailers and teasers for events
- Creating promotional graphics and videos

## PRESIDENT OF MECS

(MOTHER EARTH'S CONCERNED STUDENTS)

High School Environment Club

## 2021 - 2022

- Posting and managing social media accounts
- Setting up and planning volunteer events
- Watering garden daily

# **PROJECTS**

# KRAUSE KINETICS WEBSITE

krausekinetics.com

# **2022 - Present**

- Updating portfolio on a website
- Learning web design and UX
- Experimenting with Blender as interactive 3D feature